Strap on your boots and let's get started with our first hands on exercise.
让我们系紧鞋带来做一个Bootstrap 的练习吧 !
Sorry, just couldn't resist that.
咳 抱歉 实在忍不住这么比喻
Okay, let's get started with the first exercise.
不管怎么说 让我们开始第一个练习吧
Where we are going to learn how you would set up a web project to use Bootstrap,
在这个练习里 我们将会用 Bootstrap 来搭建一个 web 项目
how you would include Bootstrap CSS and JavaScript classes into a webpage.
我们会学习如何在网页中引用 Bootstrap CSS 和 JavaScript 类
And how to apply the Bootstrap classes to various elements in the webpage,
同时学习如何对各种  HTML 元素 应用 Bootstrap 的各种类
to design your webpage.
来设计我们的网页
First, go to your convenient location on your computer.
首先 在你电脑里你喜欢的路径处
And create a folder named conFusion.
创建一个叫 conFusion 的新文件夹
Yes, that's right conFusion.
咳 请不要太在意这个名字 【confusion 是混淆 迷惑的意思】
That's the name of the website that we're gonna create.
总之这就是我们
So let's do that first.
要创建的网站的名字
Once you create that folder, let's move into that folder and
当你创建好一个文件夹后
then we'll download Bootstrap files.
你需要下载一些 Bootstrap 文件 到这个文件夹中
Next, go to the Bootstrap website, www.getbootstrap.com, and
你可以访问 www.getbootstrap.com
then download the zip file containing the Bootstrap CSS JavaScript and font classes.
并在那下载一个打包好的压缩包
Then, move the zip file to the folder that we just created, and then unzip the file.
然后把这个压缩包解压
This will create a folder named bootstrap-3.3.5-dtxt.
这个步骤会创建一个 叫 bootstrap-3.3.5-dist 的文件夹
Move into that folder and move the three folders
将这个文件夹中的三个文件夹
inside there into the conFusion folder.
移到你创建的 conFusion 文件夹中
So let's select them and then move them to the conFusion folder.
现在让我演示一下这个搬运过程
Then move back to the conFusion folder and
选中它们 复制 然后进入 conFusion 然后粘贴即可
then now you can delete the Bootstrap distribution files.
做完搬运后 你就可以把那个 压缩包和 dist 文件夹删掉了
Now our folder is setup with the Bootstrap files, to get started on our web project.
现在我们已经做好 Bootstrap 方面的准备工作了
Next, download the index.html file that we have provided for
接下来要做的是下载我们提供的 index.html 文件
you and then move it to the conFusion folder.
把它也移到 conFusion 文件夹中
Then, you can open the index.html file in your favorite browser, and
然后你就可以用你喜欢的浏览器 打开这个 index.html
then have a look at the contents in there.
并看一看它包含了什么内容
I have already configured this html file with some content,
我已经在里面放了一些东西
which we're going to style using the Bootstrap classes.
我们接下来要做的就是 用各种 Bootstrap 类来定制它们的样式
This project creates a website for a fictitious restaurant named con Fusion.
从大体来说 这个项目为一个 叫 conFusion 的虚构的餐厅创建了一个网站
When you look at the current state of the webpage,
不过以目前的状况来看 其网页只是一些
it is plain and simple, with just the content.
朴素而简单的文字的堆砌
Looks like a typical computer science professor's webpage.
看上去像一个典型计算机学科教授的网页
At the end of this module, we're gonna take this webpage and
不过当本单元结束后 我们将会让这个页面焕然一新
then use Bootstrap classes to style it, and turn this webpage into this webpage.
所用工具当然就是各种 Bootstrap 类
You can see that the content has been appropriately styled using
最终效果大概是这样的
various Bootstrap classes, to make it a lot more attractive.
我相信这看上去有吸引力多了
And fun to look at.
各种排版也漂亮得多
So let's get started styling this webpage using Bootstrap.
那么让我们实际看看怎么实现吧
I'm going to be using Brackets as the editor of choice for this set of courses.
我将会用 Brackets 这个编辑器
You are welcome to use any text id term that you are familiar with for
当你完全可以用其它
editing the files.
你熟悉的编辑器
On the screen, you already see that I have opened the conFusion folder in Brackets,
那么此时的屏幕上
and opened the index.html file to be displayed in the window there.
你可以看到我已经打开了 index.html 文件
Now, one reason why I chose to use Brackets,
这里我想说一下 我之所以选择 Brackets
is the availability of the live preview facility in Brackets.
是因为它有动态预览的功能
If you go to the right side of the screen,
在屏幕右手侧 你可以看到这里有一个
you see this button, which looks like a thunderbolt.
闪电状的按钮
When you click on that, Brackets will automatically open
当你点击它时 Brackets 会自动在浏览器中
that webpage in a browser.
打开当前网页
And whenever you make any changes to that code, in the webpage in Brackets.
然后当你对代码作出更改时
It's automatically going to update the webpage in the browser.
网页会随着代码自动更新其内容
This is an interesting feature that makes it easy for
这是个调试神器
us to see the changes immediately in a browser.
因为你能即刻看到你代码的作用
Now because of the restriction of the screen, I am not able to show you
那么在这里 由于屏幕的限制 我无法同时向你展示
both the browser and of the Brackets window at the same time,
Brackets 和浏览器同时工作的场景
simply because it won't be very clear in the video.
如果我那样做了 这些代码 视频看上去可能就会很模糊
So I have my webpage open in my browser in a separate window, which I'm gonna switch
所以我打算做的是 在需要的时候
to occasionally to show you the changes whenever we edit the file in Brackets.
才把界面切换到浏览器那
Let's go into the index.html file, and
让我们进入 index.html 文件
then paste this code in the head of the html file.
并把这段代码拷到其头部
Now, this code sets up our webpage to be responsive.
这段代码能让我们的网页 变成响应式网页
Now, I'm going to explain the details of this code in the next set of lessons.
我会在后续几节课中阐述其实现原理
For the moment, I want to put that code into place.
目前来说 我们不必太在意细节
So that our webpage begins being responsive from the start.
只需知道它的功用即可
Next after the title in the head of the webpage,
然后在这个 title 标签下面
I'm going to add in the lines to import the Bootstrap CSS files.
要加一些代码来引入 Bootstrap CSS 文件
Finally at the bottom of the page, just before the end of the body tag,
然后就是在 body 标签下面
I am going to add in the code to import the jQuery library and
要加一些代码来引入 jQuery 库
Bootstraps JavaScript plugins.
和 Bootstrap JavaScript 插件
After we make these changes, let's go and
当我们做了这些改动后
have a look at our current state of the webpage.
让我们来看看我们的网页
Now when you switch to our webpage,
有哪些变化
you will already see that the page has changed subtly.
虽然不大 但变动还是有的
Their fonts that are being used in the page to render content, has now been
比如说其字体变成了 Bootstrap 的默认字体
updated to use the Bootstraps default fonts, which is Helvetica Neue.
也就是 Helvetica Neue
We are now going to add a container class to enclose the content of our webpage.
接下来我们要做的是加进一个"容器"
So switching back to the HTML of the page,
实现容器的方法是将其所有内容 用若干 div 标签封装
we will now go into the content and to the first div after the header,
我们以这个 header 标签下面的
so you can see that in the body of our webpage, we first have the header.
这些主体内容为例
I'm going to style the header a little bit later.
我在其外面包了若干层 div
But, we'll move to the first div inside the body and
我们先对最外层的 div
then apply the class container to this.
设置 class="container"
After this change, let's go back and have a look at our webpage.
然后让我们看看这会导致什么变化
Switching back to our webpage, you already see that
回到我们的网页
the content of a webpage is enclosed inside a container here.
你可以看到这些主体内容 都像被封装在了一个容器中
We'll still have the header and
然后抬头 主体内容 页尾这三者的
the footer as tied, which we're going to do next.
排列顺序和位置关系仍然没变
Once we upload the container class to the content of the webpage.
当我们设置好了容器之后
Inside the content, we are going to divide the content into multiple rows.
比较自然的想法 就是把容器中的内容 分成一行一行的
So to do that, for the first inner div's that we're going to encounter
为了实现这个效果 只需对设置了 class="container" 的 div 的下一层 div
inside the container, we will apply the row class to each one of them.
设置 class="row" 即可
So let's go ahead and do that, and then come back and
那么接下来让我们设置一下
have a look at the webpage again.
并看看这会给我们的网页 带来怎样的变化
We have a total of three rows in the content of our webpage.
在这个例子里 我们一共有三行
Switching back to our webpage, let's have a quick look at the change.
对应的 就要给三个 div 设置 class="row"
You won't notice much change in the webpage.
回到网页 你可能会发现 其实并没有什么变化
The content has been enclosed inside the rows,
但事实上 每一部分的内容都被单独地 放在一个"行"里面了
but we haven't applied any other styling to the webpage.
之所以没看到变化 只是因为 我们还没有应用各种定制的工具罢了
We will now move to the header,
那么来到我们网页的抬头
which is the first section of the body of our webpage.
也就是 header 这里
So to the header, I am going to apply the class of Jumbotron.
我将要对其设置 class="jumbotron"
And the first inner div inside that header,
然后对其下的第一个 div
I'm going to apply the class container.
我将要设置 class="container"
And the second inner div and better apply the class row here.
对再其下的 div 我将设置 class="row"
After these changes, let's go back and have a look at our webpage.
做完这些工作后
Switching back to our webpage.
回到我们的网页
We now see that our header has been styled using a Jumbotron.
你可以看到我们的抬头已经被定制成 一个 Bootstrap 的超大屏幕了
So, you can see the light grey background applied to the Jumbotron.
它有一个浅灰色的背景
And you can also see how the content has been rendered in the head of our webpage.
同时整个板块被渲染在了网页的抬头
You can already see the webpage taking on a good shape.
事实上到此为止 这个网页已经有模有样了
Finally, let's move to the footer of the page, and then apply the container class
最后 让我们来到页尾部分 同样地对最外层和第二层 div
to the first inner div and the row class to the second inner div in the footer.
设置 class="container" 和 class="row"
After these changes, let's have a look at our webpage.
做完这些后 让我们回到我们的网页
Now you can see that our footer has also been
你可以看到我们的页尾也被放在了
brought into the center part of our webpage.
页面居中的位置
Having one complete look at the webpage from the top to the bottom,
然后从头到尾看一遍我们的网页
you can see the Jumbotron at the top,
可以看到抬头是一个超大屏幕
then you see that the content has been enclosed inside a container.
主题内容则都被封装在了 一个容器之中
And the footer content has also been enclosed inside another container.
页尾则被封装在了另一个容器中
This completes this exercise.
以上 我们完成了这次练习
So we have now understood, how to set up our web project to use Bootstrap classes,
我们大概知道了如何用 Bootstrap 类 来搭建我们的 web 项目
and we have used some basic classes from Bootstrap to style our webpage.
和定制我们的网页 翻译: Carefree0910 | 审阅: Saul Qunming Yuan Coursera Global Translator Community